<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Daisy Theme - Christopher Nolan</title>
    <subtitle>Example &#x2F; demo page for the Daisy theme for Zola.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies-directors/christopher-nolan/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies-directors/christopher-nolan/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Oppenheimer</title>
        <published>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/oppenheimer/"/>
        <id>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/oppenheimer/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/oppenheimer/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is a 2023 epic biographical film written, produced, and directed by &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;movies-directors&#x2F;christopher-nolan&quot;&gt;Christopher Nolan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It follows the life of J. Robert Oppenheimer, the American theoretical physicist who helped develop the first nuclear weapons during World War II. Based on the 2005 biography American Prometheus by Kai Bird and Martin J. Sherwin, the film dramatizes Oppenheimer&#x27;s studies, his direction of the Los Alamos Laboratory and his 1954 security hearing. Cillian Murphy stars as Oppenheimer, alongside Robert Downey Jr. as the United States Atomic Energy Commission member Lewis Strauss. The ensemble supporting cast includes Emily Blunt, Matt Damon, Florence Pugh, Josh Hartnett, Casey Affleck, Rami Malek, and Kenneth Branagh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oppenheimer was announced in September 2021. It was Nolan&#x27;s first film not distributed by Warner Bros. Pictures since Memento (2000), due to his conflicts regarding the studio&#x27;s simultaneous theatrical and HBO Max release schedule. Murphy was the first cast member to join, with the rest joining between November 2021 and April 2022. Pre-production began by January 2022, and filming took place from February to May. The cinematographer, Hoyte van Hoytema, used a combination of IMAX 65 mm and 65 mm large-format film, including, for the first time, selected scenes in IMAX black-and-white film photography. As with many of his previous films, Nolan used extensive practical effects, with minimal compositing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oppenheimer premiered at Le Grand Rex in Paris on July 11, 2023, and was theatrically released in the United States and the United Kingdom on July 21 by Universal Pictures. Its concurrent release with Warner Bros.&#x27;s Barbie was the catalyst of the &quot;Barbenheimer&quot; phenomenon, encouraging audiences to see both films as a double feature. Oppenheimer received critical acclaim and grossed $976 million worldwide, becoming the third-highest-grossing film of 2023, the highest-grossing World War II-related film, the highest-grossing biographical film and the third-highest-grossing R-rated film of all time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipient of many accolades, Oppenheimer was nominated for thirteen awards at the 96th Academy Awards and won seven, including Best Picture, Best Director (Nolan), Best Actor (Murphy), and Best Supporting Actor (Downey). It also won five Golden Globe Awards (including Best Motion Picture – Drama) and seven British Academy Film Awards (including Best Film), and was named one of the top ten films of 2023 by the National Board of Review and the American Film Institute.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This text is based on the article &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Oppenheimer_(film)&quot;&gt;Oppenheimer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the free encyclopedia Wikipedia and is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;creativecommons.org&#x2F;licenses&#x2F;by-sa&#x2F;4.0&#x2F;deed.de&quot;&gt;Creative Commons CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;w&#x2F;index.php?title=Oppenheimer_(film)&amp;amp;action=history&quot;&gt;list of authors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is available on Wikipedia.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Interstellar</title>
        <published>2014-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2014-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/interstellar/"/>
        <id>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/interstellar/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/daisy/movies/interstellar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is a 2014 epic science fiction film directed by &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;movies-directors&#x2F;christopher-nolan&quot;&gt;Christopher Nolan&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Jonathan. It stars Matthew McConaughey, Anne Hathaway, Jessica Chastain, Bill Irwin, Ellen Burstyn, and Michael Caine. Set in a dystopian future where Earth is suffering from catastrophic blight and famine, the film follows a group of astronauts who travel through a wormhole near Saturn in search of a new home for mankind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screenplay had its origins in a script Jonathan developed in 2007 and was originally set to be directed by Steven Spielberg. Theoretical physicist Kip Thorne was an executive producer and scientific consultant on the film, and wrote the tie-in book The Science of Interstellar. It was Lynda Obst&#x27;s final film as producer before her death. Cinematographer Hoyte van Hoytema shot it on 35 mm film in the Panavision anamorphic format and IMAX 70 mm. Filming began in late 2013 and took place in Alberta, Klaustur, and Los Angeles. Interstellar uses extensive practical and miniature effects, and the company DNEG created additional digital effects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interstellar was released in theaters on November 7, 2014. In the United States, it was first released on film stock, expanding to venues using digital projectors. The film received generally positive reviews and grossed $681 million worldwide during its initial theatrical run, making it the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2014. Among its various accolades, Interstellar was nominated for five awards at the 87th Academy Awards, winning Best Visual Effects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This text is based on the article &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Interstellar_(film)&quot;&gt;Interstellar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from the free encyclopedia Wikipedia and is licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;creativecommons.org&#x2F;licenses&#x2F;by-sa&#x2F;4.0&#x2F;deed.de&quot;&gt;Creative Commons CC-BY-SA 4.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;w&#x2F;index.php?title=Interstellar_(film)&amp;amp;action=history&quot;&gt;list of authors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is available on Wikipedia.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
