<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>ski</title>
      <link>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/</link>
      <description>A minimalist Zola theme inspired by Swiss design principles.</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Markdown</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Bedir Ekim</author>
          <link>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/markdown/</link>
          <guid>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/markdown/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/markdown/">&lt;p&gt;A lightweight markup language designed to be easy to read and write.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;headers&quot;&gt;Headers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;md&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-md &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-md&quot; data-lang=&quot;md&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;# Title 1
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;## Title 2
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;### Title 3
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;#### Title 4
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;##### Title 5
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;###### Title 6
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This text is italic.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;This text is bold.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subitem 1.1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subitem 1.2&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 2
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subitem 2.1&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subitem 2.2&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Item 3&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mercury&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venus&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mars&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupiter&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturn&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uranus&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neptune&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;link&quot;&gt;Link&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;un1970ix.com&quot;&gt;Bedir Ekim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;image&quot;&gt;Image&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;salif.github.io&#x2F;zola-themes-collection&#x2F;demo&#x2F;ski&#x2F;articles&#x2F;markdown&#x2F;matterhorn.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Matterhorn&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-block&quot;&gt;Code Block&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;println!(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hello, world!&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#eceff4;&quot;&gt;;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;table&quot;&gt;Table&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Point&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Canton&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Diablerets&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Vaud&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Piz Bernina&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Grisons&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Finsteraarhorn&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bern&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The Promise of UNIX: A New Era</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 1971 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Bedir Ekim</author>
          <link>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/unix/</link>
          <guid>https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/unix/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://salif.github.io/zola-themes-collection/demo/ski/articles/unix/">&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving world of computing, where machines grow faster and more complex, a new development is emerging that promises to revolutionize how we think about software systems. That development is UNIX, a new operating system born out of the minds of brilliant engineers and mathematicians at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs. UNIX is a system that breaks away from tradition, offering a radically simple, yet powerful way of managing and interacting with computers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIX is not just another operating system. It is a new philosophy of computing. It is built on a foundation of simplicity, flexibility, and portability. At its heart, UNIX embodies the belief that a computer should be a tool, one that is easily accessible and understandable, yet powerful enough to tackle the most complex tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most remarkable features of UNIX is its use of the file as a central concept. Everything, from text files to devices like printers, is treated as a file in UNIX. This unified approach to system management simplifies interaction with the machine and allows the user to think in terms of simple, well-defined operations. By doing so, UNIX enables a level of control and adaptability that is unparalleled in the world of mainframes and minicomputers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, UNIX is built with multitasking in mind. This means that multiple programs can run simultaneously on the same machine, allowing for a more efficient use of resources. The use of small, specialized programs that can be combined and piped together further enhances the system&#x27;s flexibility. It is a philosophy known as building blocks, where the emphasis is on creating simple, reliable tools that can be connected in creative ways to perform complex tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps the most revolutionary aspect of UNIX is its portability. Unlike other operating systems, which are designed for specific hardware, UNIX can be adapted to work on a wide range of machines. This is made possible through its development in the C programming language, which was specifically designed to be portable. As a result, UNIX is capable of running on everything from small minicomputers to large, powerful mainframes, making it an ideal choice for academic institutions, research labs, and commercial enterprises alike.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision behind UNIX is not just about improving the efficiency of computing. It is about democratizing access to powerful tools. In the future, it is believed that systems like UNIX will pave the way for a more open and accessible computing environment, where users from various fields can all contribute to and benefit from a shared software ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we stand at the dawn of this new era, UNIX holds great promise for the future. It is still in its early stages, but it is clear that this system will play a pivotal role in shaping the way we work with computers for years to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where computing is becoming ever more intricate and sophisticated, UNIX reminds us that the simplest ideas can often lead to the most profound advancements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us embrace this new way of thinking, for it may just be the key to unlocking the full potential of our machines and, by extension, our future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
